Guide to the New-York Historical Society Collection of Caricatures and Cartoons 1643, 1756-1943, 1977 PR 10
New-York Historical Society
- Series III. Jacksonian Period, 1828-1840
  - The Disappointed Abolitionists [Graft re Abolition], 1838 (Folder FF-44, Item 1838-14)
    Caricature of matter re: David Ruggles, John Darg, Barney Corse, and Isaac Hopper. Lithograph: Signed C. (E.W. Clay). Printed and Published by H.R. Robinson, New York. Acquisition(?) date on front: May 29, 19/08.
  - British Warfare in 1812, 1837-38, 1838 (Folder FF-44, Item 1838-15)
    Hand-colored lithograoh printed and published by H.R. Robinson, New York. This caricature is based on "Philanthropie Moderne" (See 1812-4). Acquisition(?) date on front: June 10, 1904.
  - Machines for the New Pay-Tent Office., 1838 (Folder FF-44, Item 1838-16)
    Hand-colored ithograph: By O'Graphic, Right, signed C. (E.W. Clay). Printed and published by H.R. Robinson, New York. Stamped on front, "From Judge Mitchells Collection".
  - Whig Magnets Attreacted by the Pole. [Van Buren], 1838 (Folder FF-44, Item 1838-17)
    Lithograph: signed EWC (E.W. Clay). Published by J. Childs, Lithographers, New York. Stamped on front, "From Judge Mitchells Collection"; Stamped on back, "Gift of Henry O. Havermeyer, Yale 1900. Collection of the United States Naval Prints and Painting". Sent as a letter: addressed to H.B. Alden, Belfast, Maine. From: P.M.
  - The Effects of Loco-Foco Pledges, 1838 (Folder FF-44, Item 1838-18)
    Lithograph: signed HD (H. Dacre). Printed and published by H.R. Robinson, New York. Acquisition(?) date on front: Feb. 3, 1906.
  - The Political Drill of the State Officers [New York State Politics]., 1838 (Folder FF-44, Item 1838-19)
    Lithograph of C. Van Benthuysen, Albany, NY. Illustration followed by four columns of a letter to the editor of the Albany Arguslengthy text]
  - The Rebound of the Ball [Van Buren and Sub-Treassury], 1838 (Folder FF-45, Item 1838-20)
    Hand-colored lithpgraph printed and published by H.R. Robinson, New York. Acquisition date on back: December 23, 1954.
  - The Three Mares ["res" crossed out and "yors" substituted to spell Mayors], New York Course, Spring Races, 1838. [New York City Politics] (Folder FF-45, Item 1838-21)
    Hand-colored lithograph: Shank fecit. Printed and published by H.R. Robinson, New York. Acquisition(?) date on front: May 29, 19/04.
  - The Globe-Man after Hearing of the Vote on the Sub-Treasury Bill [Financial Policy], 1838 (Folder FF-45, Item 1838-23)
    Lithograph printed and published by H.R. Robinson, New York. Acquisition(?) date on front: Sept. 23, 1901.
  - Great Loco Foco Juggernaut. A New Console-A-Tory Sub-Treasury Rag-Monster. [Jackson, Van Buren], 1838 (Folder FF-45, Item 1838-24)
    Etching - perhaps D.C. Johnston. Stamped on front, "From Judge Mitchells Collection"; Stamped on back, "Gift of Henry O. Havermeyer, Yale 1900. Collection of the United States Naval Prints and Painting". Same as 1838-30.
  - Executive Marcy ["a" crossed out, "e" substituted] and the Bambers, 1838 (Folder FF-45, Item 1838-25)
    Hand-colored lithograph: signed C. (E.W. Clay). Printed and published by H.R. Robinson, New York. Caricature 1838-26 has the same title, but is not identical. Acquisition(?) date on front: June 10, 1904.
  - Executive Marcy ["a" crossed out, "e" substituted] and the Bambers, 1838 (Folder FF-45, Item 1838-26)
    Hand-colored lithograph: signed C. (E.W. Clay). Printed and published by H.R. Robinson, New York. Caricature 1838-25 has same title but is not identical. Acquisition(?) date on front: June 10, June 10, 1904.
  - The Mayor ["yor" crossed out, "re" substituted] Frightened at a Phoenix [New York City Politics], 1838 (Folder FF-45, Item 1838-27)
    Lithograph published by J. Childs, New York.
  - Sub Treasurers Meeting in England., 1838 (Folder FF-45, Item 1838-28)
    Hand-colored lithograph printed and published by H.R. Robinson, New York. Acquisition(?) date on front: May 29, 1904.
  - Loco Foco Scramble for Collectors Licenses. [Van Buren Campaign], 1838 (Folder FF-45, Item 1838-29)
    Hand-colored lithograph printed and published by H.R. Robinson, New York. Acquisition(?) date on front: Sept. 29, 1901.
  - Great Loco Foco Juggernaut. A New Console-A-Tory Sub-Treasury Rag-Monster. [Jackson, Van Buren], 1838 (Folder FF-45, Item 1838-30)
    Same caricature as 1838-24. Acquisition(?) date on front: Dec. 6, 1950.
  - The Treasury-Hen Alarmed [Van Buren], 1839 (Folder FF-46, Item 1839-1)
    Hand-colored lithograph printed and published by H.R. Robinson, New York. Stamped on back: "Gift of Henry O. Havermeyer, Yale 1900. Collection of the United States Naval Prints and Paintings".
  - Called to Account [Henry Wise], 1839 (Folder FF-46, Item 1839-2)
    Hand-colored lithograph printed and published by H.R. Robinson, New York. Acquisition(?) date on front: July 12, 19/14.
  - Senate Chamber U.S.A. Conclusion of Clay's Speech In Defence of Slavery [Henry Clay, John Calhoun], 1839 (Folder FF-46, Item 1839-3)
    Lithograph. Pencil note on back dates Henry Clay's related speech in Senate to Feb. 7, 1839. Newspaper clipping affixed to lithograph. Acquisition(?) date on front: April 6, 1906.
  - Symptoms of a Duel [Henry Wise/ Levi Woodbury], 1839 (Folder FF-46, Item 1839-4)
    Hand-colored ithograph printed and published by H.R. Robinson, New York. Stamped on back: "Gift of Henry O. Havermeyer, Yale 1900. Collection of the United States Naval Prints and Paintings".
  - The Man Wot Pays No Postage [Post Office Dept], 1839 (Folder FF-46, Item 1839-5)
    Hand-colored lithograph: Signed M.S.(?) Printed and published by H.R. Robinson, New York. Acquisition(?) date on front: July 12, 1904.
  - The Meeting at Saratoga. Like Boxers thus before they fight, their hands in friendship they unite. [Van Buren and Clay], 1839 (Folder FF-46, Item 1839-6)
    Lith of H.R. Robinson. Acquisition(?) date on front: Sept. 27, 1907.
  - Struggle for the Presidency ["si" crossed out, "ce" substituted] Between V. B...N and Black Bess, [Presidential Race], 1839 (Folder FF-46, Item 1839-7)
    Lithograph: Lith. & Pub. by Baker, New York.
  - A Bull Chase, "The Words of the Wise, are as Goads" [Henry Wise/Levi Woodbury], 1839 (Folder FF-46, Item 1839-8)
    Lithograph printed and published by H.R. Robinson, New York. Acquisition(?) date on front: April 16, 1914.
  - Abolition Frowned Down. [Abolition], 1839 (Folder FF-46, Item 1839-9)
  - Presentation [Van Buren, Haiti Ambassador], 1839 (Folder FF-46, Item 1839-10)
  - Practical Amalgamation (The Wedding) [Abolition, Intermarriage], 1839 (Folder FF-46, Item 1839-11)
    Handcolored lithograph: E.W. Clay inv et fec. Published by John Childs, New York. "Also just published - The Amalgamation Waltz - The Courtship - The Fruits - Johnny Q. - Black Cat." Acquisition(?) date on front: May 5, 19/05.
  - The Cut Direct. Or a Scene in High Life at Saratoga Springs., 1839 (Folder FF-46, Item 1839-12)
    Lithograph: Lith. of H.R. Robinson, New York.
  - Worse than a Spanish Inquisition, 1839 (Folder FF-46, Item 1839-13)
    Lithograph printed and published by H.R. Robinson, New York.
  - Fanny Ellsler's [sic] Last Serenade, Or The Soap-Locks Disgraceful Attack upon the Germans [Social], 1840 (Folder FF-47, Item 1840-1)
    Lithograph printed and published by H.R. Robinson, New York. Acquisition(?) date on front: May 29, 19/04.
  - The North Bend Farmer and his Visitors [Van Buren et al., William Henry Harrison], 1840 (Folder FF-47, Item 1840-2)
    Lithograph: (2 copies; one colored): Signed HD (H. Dacre). Printed and published by H.R. Robinson, New York.
  - A Political Movement [Van Buren Election Loss to Harrison], 1840 (Folder FF-47, Item 1840-3)
    Lithograph: (2 copies; 1 colored): signed HD (H. Dacre). Printed and published by H.R. Robinson, New York and Washington DC. Copy 1 dated on front, Sept. 27, 1901. Copy 2 stamped on front "From Judge Mitchells Collection; stamped on back: "Gift of Henry O. Havermeyer, Yale 1900. Collection of the United States Naval Prints and Paintings".
  - Full Tilt for the Capitol. [Van Buren], 1840 (Folder FF-47, Item 1840-4)
    Lithograph: Signed HD (H. Dacre). Lithographed and published by H.R. Robinson, New York and Washington DC.
  - Rats Quitting the Ship [Van Buren, Kendall, Blair], 1840 (Folder FF-47, Item 1840-5)
    Handcolored lithograph: signed HD (H. Dacre). Printed and published H.R. Robinson, New York and Washington DC. Stamped on front, "From Judge Mitchells Collection; stamped on back: "Gift of Henry O. Havermeyer, Yale 1900. Collection of the United States Naval Prints and Paintings".
  - The New Era Whig Trap Sprung [Van Buren and Jackson], 1840 (Folder FF-47, Item 1840-6)
    Lithograph (2 copies; 1 colored): Signed Bonnyshanks (Attributed to N. Sarony). Printed and published H.R. Robinson, New York and Washington DC. Copy 1: Acquisition: Gift of Mrs. DeWitt Lockman, Sept. 7, 1927. Copy 2: Stamped on front, "From Judge Mitchells Collection"; stamped on back: "Gift of Henry O. Havermeyer, Yale 1900. Collection of the United States Naval Prints and Paintings".
  - Presidential Election. [Van Buren v. Harrison], 1840 (Folder FF-48, Item 1840-7)
  - Going Down. Going Up [Van Buren v. Harrison Election], 1840 (Folder FF-48, Item 1840-8)
    Lithograph: Signed EWC (E.W. Clay). Published by J. Childs, New York. Acquisition(?) date on front: Feb. 21, 18/99.
  - The Northern Man with Southern Principles [Van Buren, African-American Testimony], 1840 (Folder FF-48, Item 1840-9)
    Lithograph: Signed Bonnyshanks (Attributed to N. Sarony). Printed and published by H.R. Robinson, New York and Washington DC. Acquisition(?) date on front: June 10, 1904.
  - Above: The Nation is Whig! "Tell Chapman to Crow" Below: North Bend Game Cock. [Harrison Election, Tippecanoe], 1840 (Folder FF-48, Item 1840-10)
    Hand-colored lithograph: Signed Nosey. Printed and published by H.R. Robinson, New York and Washington DC. "Respectfully dedicated to Robert C. Wetmore, Esq. President of the North Bend Association of New York, by his obt servant" signed H.R. Robinson. Acquisition(?) date on front: June 10, 19/04.
  - Granny Harrison Delivering the Country of the Executive Federalist [Harrison & Calhoun], 1840 (Folder FF-49, Item 1840-11)
    Handcolored lithograph printed and published by H.R. Robinson, New York & Washington DC. Stamped on front, "From Judge Mitchells Collection" Stamped on back, "The Gift of Henry O. Havermeyer, Yale 1900. Collection of United States Naval Prints and Painting"
  - The Illustrious Footsteps [Van Buren & Jackson], 1840 (Folder FF-49, Item 1840-12)
    Lithograph, possibly by Sarony, published by J. Childs, New York. Stamped on front, "From Judge Mitchells Collection" Stamped on back, "The Gift of Henry O. Havermeyer, Yale 1900. Collection of United States Naval Prints and Painting"
  - Specie Claws., 1840 (Folder FF-49, Item 1840-13)
    Handcolored lithograph by H.D. (H. Dacres); printed and published by H.R. Robinson, New York. Acquisition (?) date on front: Sept. 27, 1901[1907].
  - Political Jugglers Losing Their Balance [Van Buren, Harrison, et. al.], 1840 (Folder FF-49, Item 1840-14)
    Lithograph: EWC (E.W. Clay), published by J. Childs, New York. Acquisition (?) date on front: Feb. 21, 18/99.
  - Chapman Trying to Crow [National Politics], 1840 (Folder FF-49, Item 1840-15)
    Handcolored lithograph printed and published by H.R. Robinson, New York & Washington, DC. Dated on front, Sept. 27, 1901[1907?]7.
  - The Last Card. Tip Overthrown.[Van Buren], 1840 (Folder FF-49, Item 1840-16)
    Handcolored lithograph signed Spoodlyks 1840. Printed and published by H.R. Robinson, New York. Acquisition (?) date on front: July 12, 19/04.
  - Funeral of Loco Focoism [Loco Foco], 1840 (Folder FF-49, Item 1840-17)
    Lithograph signed EWC (E.W. Clay), published by John Childs (misspelled as Cheilds), New York. Stamped on front, "From Judge Mitchells Collection" Stamped on back, "The Gift of Henry O. Havermeyer, Yale 1900. Collection of United States Naval Prints and Painting"
  - A Globe to LIVE ON! [F.P. Blair & Amos Kendall], 1840 (Folder FF-49, Item 1840-18)
    Lithograph signed N.S. (Sarony?), printed and published by H.R. Robinson, New York & Washington, DC. Acquisition (?) date on front: July 08/03.
  - This is the House that Jack Built [Jackson & Van Buren], 1840 (Folder FF-49, Item 1840-19)
    Lithograph signed EWC (E.W. Clay), printed by John Childs, New York. Stamped on front, "From Judge Mitchells Collection" Stamped on back, "The Gift of Henry O. Havermeyer, Yale 1900. Collection of United States Naval Prints and Painting"
  - The New Era, or the Effects of a Standing Army (2 copies), 1840 (Folder FF-49, Item 1840-20)
    2 copies. Lithograph signed N. Sarony, printed and published by H.R. Robinson, New York. Copy 1: Acquisition (?) date on front: July 12, 1902 [1904?]. Copy 2: Acquisition (?) date on back: Dec. 6, 1950.
  - Sub-Treasury System, or Office Holders Elysium. [Van Buren et. al.], 1840 (Folder FF-49, Item 1840-21)
    Handcolored lithograph printed and published by H.R. Robinson, New York. Stamped on front, "From Judge Mitchells Collection" Stamped on back, "The Gift of Henry O. Havermeyer, Yale 1900. Collection of United States Naval Prints and Painting"
  - The People Versus Monopoly. [Hudson River Steamboat Association/Hancox's Napoleon], 1840 (Folder FF-50, Item 1840-22)
    Handcolored lithograph printed by J. Childs, New York.
  - Expansion & Contraction, As witnessed in the Senate March 5, 1840, during Mr. Buchanan's remarks on the currency. [F.P. Blair & Dixon Hall Lewis] (Folder FF-50, Item 1840-23)
    Handcolored lithograph printed and published by H.R. Robinson, New York & Washington, DC. Acquisition(?) date on front: July 12, 19/04.
  - Clar De Kitchen [Harrison & Van Buren], 1840 (Folder FF-50, Item 1840-24)
    Lithograph signed Bonneyshanks. Printed and published by H.R. Robinson, New York & Washington, DC. Written in pencil on the back, "Gift of Mr. DeWitt M. Lockman. Sept. 7, 1927"
  - Disturbing a Martins Nest. [Van Buren], 1840 (Folder FF-50, Item 1840-25)
    Handcolored lithograph printed and published by H.R. Robinson, New York. Acquisition(?) date on front: June 10, 1904.
  - A Bivouack in Safety, or Florida Troops Preventing a Surprise. This inhuman war has already cost the people of the United States $30,000,000 without any prospect of its being brought to a termination., 1840 (Folder FF-50, Item 1840-26)
    Lithograph signed HD (H. Dacre), printed and published by H.R. Robinson, New York & Washngton, DC. Acquisition(?) date on front: Sept. 27, 1901 [1907?]7.
  - The Wolf Bent-On, Meeting Little Red Riding Hood [Van Buren], 1840 (Folder FF-50, Item 1840-27)
    Lithograph published by H.R. Robinson, New York. Acquisition(?) date on front: June 3, 1908 (?)
  - An Affecting Scene in Kentucky [Richard Mentor Johnson and His Relationship with Julia Chinn], 1840 (Folder FF-50, Item 1840-28 (Copy 1))
    Lithograph: anonymous. Acquisition date on back: Nov. 16, 1942.
  - O.K. Respectfully dedicated to the members of the Eighth Ward Tippecanoe Club, and Inscribed to their Patriotic Chairman Charles H. Delavan, Esq. [NYC Politics], 1840 (Folder FF-50, Item 1840-29)
    Lith and published by H.R. Robinson, New York & Washington, DC. Acquisition(?) date on front: May 29, 1904[?].
  - [Expansion & Contraction] (Title trimmed off), 1840 (Folder FF-50, Item 1840-30)
    Lithograph: same image as 1840-23, but not colored.
  - [Clar De Kitchen] (No title), 1840 (Folder FF-50, Item 1840-31)
    Image is the same as 1840-24. Image appears to be hand-drawn.
  - [Original Drawing], 1840 (Folder FF-50, Item 1840-32)
    Drawings of figures, including Van Buren.
- Series IV. Antebellum Period, 1841-1859
  The series includes about 238 caricatures dating from the two decades (1841-1959) prior to the Civil War. Most of the caricatures relate to the Presidential election campaigns of 1844, 1848, 1852, and 1856. Candidates featured include Henry Clay and James Polk (1844); Zachary Taylor, Lewis Cass, and Martin Van Buren (1848); Franklin Pierce and Winfield Scott (1852); and James Buchanan, John C. Frémont, and Millard Fillmore (1856). In addition to the principals, the vice-president candidates and major politicians affiliated with the candidate's parties or positions appear in the caricatures. The aging Andrew Jackson appears frequently in the caricatures of the early 1840s in association with Martin Van Buren and the Democratic Party. Similarly, Martin ("Matty") Van Buren also appears frequently during this period either as a principal in a presidential election or in the background connecting him to the Democratic Party. Among other individuals appearing are John Tyler, John Calhoun, Horace Greeley, and P.T. Barnum.
  The themes of the caricatures touch on the major national issues of the 1840s-1850s, primarily in the context of presidential campaigns and party platforms, though also as standalone images. Images concerning slavery and abolition are found throughout the series, especially in the context of the Texas annexation, the dispute over whether to admit Kansas as a free or slave state ("Bleeding Kansas"), the possible acquisition of Cuba, the Fugitive Slave Act of 1850, and others. One image portrays the emergence of escapee Henry "Box" Brown from his box.
  Other themes represented with at least a few caricatures are the War with Mexico (1846), the Wilmot Proviso (1846), the Oregon Territory border dispute (1846), the California Gold Rush (1849), and the Panic of 1857. Social caricatures include those related to the increasing role of women outside the domestic sphere and the working class men known as "b'hoys."
  Among the caricaturists that are particularly well-represented in the series are: H.R. Robinson, J. Childs, E.W. (Edward Williams) Clay, James S. Baillie, H. Buoholzer (H. Bucholzer), Nathaniel Currier (beginning 1844), Sarony & Major, F. & S. Palmer, and John L. Magee.
  - John Tyler Attempts to Escape from the Tyler Platform, Which Stands on Three Legs, to the Democratic Platform, and is Repelled by the Globe and Enquirer. [Tyler, Newspapers, Van Buren, Others], 1841 (Folder FF-51, Item 1841-1)
    Wood Engraving: Anonymous. N-YHS copy has additional figures pasted over left side of picture. Acquisition(?) date on front: Nov. 26, 1923.
  - The Captain & Corporal's Guard [Tyler et. al.], 1841 (Folder FF-51, Item 1841-2)
    Handcolored lithograph printed and published by H.R. Robinson, New York & Washington, DC.
  - Black and White Slaves [Slavery], 1841 (Folder FF-51, Item 1841-3)
    Lithograph signed EWC (E.W. Clay), published by A. Donnelly, New York. Contrasts American slavery (happy enslaved blacks taken care of by their masters) with that of England (poor whites in misery exploited by the rich).
  - Notice to Quit. March 4th 1841 [Harrison Victory over Van Buren] (Folder FF-51, Item 1841-4)
    Lith. and published by J. Childs, New York. Acquisition(?) date on front: Feb. 21, 18/99.
  - The Triumph of Liberality and Justice. [Gov. Seward], 1842 (Folder FF-51, Item 1842-1)
    Lithograph signed HD (H. Dacre), published by H.R. Robinson, New York.
  - Impure Spirits Disappearing before the Rising Sun. [Clay, Jackson, Van Buren] (2 copies), 1843 (Folder FF-51, Item 1843-1)
    2 copies. Lithograph signed EWC (E.W. Clay); W.R. Willis, Lith., New York. Copy 1: Acquisition(?) date on front: June 3, 19/08. Copy 2 is stamped on front, "From Judge Mitchells Collection" Stamped on back, "The Gift of Henry O. Havermeyer, Yale 1900. Collection of United States Naval Prints and Painting"
  - Governor Dorr's Extra! [Dorr's Rebellion], 1843 (Folder FF-51, Item 1843-2)
    Wood Engraving: Anonymous. Acquisition(?) date on front: May 20, 1908. Pencil note on back states Copy 2 is in Broadsides.
  - Faneuil Hall (misspelled as Fanueil Hall). A Boston Notion for the World's Fair, A New Cradle of Liberty. [Abolition/Massachusetts Passage of Personal Liberty Act], 1843 (Folder FF-51, Item 1843-3)
    Wash Drawing by EWC (E.W. Clay).
  - St. David Playing the Devil with the Apple Women in the Exchange [David Hale/New York Journal of Commerce], 1844 (Folder FF-52, Item c.1844-1)
    Lithograph: anonymous. Acquisition(?) date on front: March 6, 19/05.
  - Great Presidential Steeple Chase of 1844. Coming In - Odds 10-1 on Old Kentucky. [Clay, Van Buren et. al.] (Folder FF-52, Item 1844-2)
    Lithograph signed EWC (E.W. Clay), published by A. Donnelly, New York.
  - Handicap Race Presidential Stakes 1844 [Clay, Van Buren, et al.] (Folder FF-52, Item 1844-3)
    Lithograph signed EWC (E.W. Clay), published by J. Childs, New York. Stamped on front, "From Judge Mitchells Collection" Stamped on back, "The Gift of Henry O. Havermeyer, Yale 1900. Collection of United States Naval Prints and Painting"
  - A Caster, Or Many a Slip 'twixt the Hand and the Lip. [Polk, McLane & Brit. King], 1844 (Folder FF-52, Item 1844-4)
    Lithograph: anonymous. Acquisition(?) date on front: Feb. 25, 18/96.
  - Ground & Lofty Tumbling. [Clay, Frelinghuysen, Election of 1844] (Folder FF-52, Item 1844-5)
    Handcolored lithograph signed H. Buoholzer, lith. and published by J. Baillie, New York. Acquisition(?) date on front: June 3, 19/08.
  - A View of the Political World from Kinderhook. [Van Buren], 1844 (Folder FF-52, Item 1844-6)
    Lithograph published by E. Jones, New York. Acquisition(?) date on front: June 3, 1908.
  - A Triumphal Entry into the White House after the Manner of the Ancients. [Election of 1844, Clay, Calhoun, et al] (Folder FF-52, Item 1844-7)
    Lithograph: EWC (E.W. Clay), published by A. Donnelly, New York. Stamped on front, "From Judge Mitchells Collection" Stamped on back, "The Gift of Henry O. Havermeyer, Yale 1900. Collection of United States Naval Prints and Painting"
  - Weighed and Found Wanting, Or the Effects of a Summer's Ramble. [Van Buren, Clay], 1844 (Folder FF-52, Item 1844-8 (Copy 1))
    Lithograph signed HD (H. Dacre), printed and published by H.R. Robinson, New York
  - Requesting Him to Resign, Or the End of the Weathercock Dynasty (Title cut off) [Election of 1844, Tyler, Clay, et al.] (Folder FF-52, Item 1844-9)
    Lithograph signed by Buoholzer, lith. and published by J. Baillie, New York. Acquisition(?) date on front: June 3, 19/08.
  - The Polka, A New National Dance Adopted by the Democratic Convention at Baltimore May 29th,1844. [1844 Election, Calhoun, Tyler, Polk, et al.] (Folder FF-52, Item 1844-10)
    Lithograph signed by EWC (E.W. Clay), published by A. Donnelly, New York, sold by A. H. Purdy, New York. Acquisition(?) date on front: March 26, 1907.
  - Polk in his Extremity. [Election of 1844, Polk, Clay, et al.] (Folder FF-53, Item 1844-11)
    Lithograph: Lith. and published by J. Baillie, New York. Stamped on front, "From Judge Mitchells Collection" Stamped on back, "The Gift of Henry O. Havermeyer, Yale 1900. Collection of United States Naval Prints and Painting"
  - Balloon Acension to the Presidential Chair. [Election of 1844, Clay, Polk, et al.] (Folder FF-53, Item 1844-13)
    Lithograph signed H. Buoholzer, lith and published by J. Baillie, New York. Stamped on front, "From Judge Mitchells Collection" Stamped on back, "The Gift of Henry O. Havermeyer, Yale 1900. Collection of United States Naval Prints and Painting"
  - The Pedlars. [Election of 1844, Clay, Frelinghuysen] (Folder FF-53, Item 1844-14)
    Lithograph lith. and published by J. Baillie, New York.
  - Not a Drum was Heard Nor a Funeral Note... [Election of 1844, Clay, et al]] (Folder FF-53, Item 1844-15)
    Lithograph signed by H. Buoholzer, lith. and published by J. Baillie, New York.
  - The Masked Battery or Loco-Foco Strate(gy.) [Election of 1844, Polk, Clay, Texas] (Folder FF-53, Item 1844-16)